

PAT COLLINS

WORKING IN INDUSTRIAL AUTOMATION
ASPIRING TO BECOME A FRONT END DEVELOPER

EDUCATION

MAINTENANCE AND
REALIABILITY ENGINEERING
AUT University

CERTIFICATE IV IN
INSTRUMENTATION,
MEASUREMENT AND CONTROL
Perth, WA

ELECTRICAL TRADE CERTIFICATE (CERT III IN ELECTRO TECHNOLOGY)

Taranaki, New Zealand

KEY COMPETENCIES

- Strong analytical and problem-solving skills
- Proven ability to cope under pressure
- Calm disposition
- Good written, oral, and interpersonal skills
- Excellent decision-making skills
- Honest and dependable
- Keen interest in new technology and software

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

I have over ten years of experience based in engineering and technical services, most recently in Industrial Programming.

I'm currently upskilling to become a Front End Developer. I'm familiar with JavaScript, HTML and CSS. I possess a strong ability to quickly comprehend new or existing systems and solve problems. My abilities stem from understanding and programming industrial automation and control systems.

Prior to beginning my industrial career, I spent two years in the Royal New Zealand Army.

EXPERIENCE

AUTOMATION TECHNICIAN

Day to day operations (2017 – Present) Employer: SAGE Automation

- Providing urgent, programming, and electrical support on automated machinery and equipment, to a range of customers over varying industries and systems.
- Remote support and programming.
- SCADA programming upgrades and commissioning.
- Utilising numerous platforms and languages, including ladderlogic, structured text and function block.
- Delivering continuous improvement, preventative, corrective and recommended maintenance, and documentation.
- Field instrument calibrations and testing.

AUTOMATION TECHNICIAN

FMG/Downer – Chinchester Solar Farm Project (2021) Employer: SAGE Automation

- Commissioning Cloudbreak substation SCADA system. Utilising Rockwell FactoryTalk View ME and Studio5000 software.
- Communications protocol DNP3 was used to send and receive signals to various devices such as HV protection relays.
- PLC code was adjusted as required.



PAT COLLINS

WORKING IN INDUSTRIAL AUTOMATION
ASPIRING TO BECOME A FRONT END DEVELOPER

TECHNOLOGY EXPERIENCE

- JavaScript, HTML and CSS
- PLC programming across multiple platforms and languages
- HMI programming
- SCADA Systems and network architecture
- Communications & networking

EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

AUTOMATION TECHNICIAN

Kimberly Port – Broome Cruise Ship Access Platform (2019) Employer: SAGE Automation

 Commissioning an automated platform. Establishing communications between field devices and PLCs, adjusting the PLC program as required, and tuned analogue inputs. Creating logic in the program to run Powerflex 527 automation drives and redlined any drawing changes.

AUTOMATION TECHNICIAN

Orora Fiber Packaging – Shredder Pit Commissioning (2018) Employer: SAGE Automation

- Commissioning an automated cardboard shredding system, incorporating a new PLC and automation controls into an old system.
- Performing continuous improvement after the initial design and installation, and introducing torque-following between two drives, which compensated for problems created by mechanical interlocking of shredding motors.

ELECTRICAL AND INSTRUMENTATION TECHNICIAN

Employer: Austral Bricks (2013 – 2016)

 As a E&I Technician, gaining experience in conveyor control, VSDs, PLCs, Extruders, Citect SCADA, relay logic-controlled equipment, gas heated kilns and brick processing machinery, PID controllers, and many other unique but interesting automated equipment.

INDUSTRIAL MAINTENANCE ELECTRICIAN

Employer: Fonterra Diary (2008 – 2013)

- Leading the electrical maintenance and servicing of the whey products plant resulting in efficient and prioritised repairs.
- Working in the following plants during this time with Fonterra: Co-generation (gas turbines and power generation), cheese, milk powder, milk treatment, butter and cold storage.
- Fonterra is a world leader in the dairy industry, all these plants were an introduction into modern and autonomous production.